"When you're setting up a campaign with manual keyword targeting, the match type determines
how closely the keywords you bid on match the shopping queries customers are using.
Because
broad match gives you the highest traffic exposure of any of the match types, it's
best for driving awareness or to learn which terms customers use, helping you refine campaigns
later on.
Let's take the example of a set of blue cotton sheets that you're advertising
and you've included blue cotton sheets in your keywords.
This one keyword is a combination
of three terms – blue, cotton and sheets.
If you're using the broad match type, your
ad may display when customers browse using all three of those terms in any order, plus
close variations like plurals.
If customers use other terms along with these anywhere in
their queries, your ad may also appear.
(
upbeat music)